Inventory of the Byers Family Papers 1806-1928
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Miscellaneous, 1839-1906, n.d. (Box-folder 4:3-4)
  - Miscellaneous material, 1839,1890-1893, 1906, n.d., 63 items. (Box-folder 4:3)
    Miscellaneous material including a letter, 1 Jan. 1839, from Briscoe G. Baldwin, n.p., to W[illia]m Shumate, Mount Sidney, Virginia, concerning the hire of "a smart, healthy, and likely Negro fellow…as a blacksmith"; report cards, 1890-1893, of Edwin C. and H[oward] S. Byers at Augusta Classical and Military Academy, Fort Defiance, Virginia; blue print of the "Holbrook Transition Spiral condensed for practical work," 1906; assorted recipes, grocery lists, laborer's records; and school and penmanship exercises, some by S[amuel] B. Weller.
  - Miscellaneous envelopes, n.d. (Box-folder 4:4)
  Series 6: Ledger and Account Books
- Ledger and Account Books, 1806-1902., Manuscript Volumes. MsV. 1-14 (Box-folder 5:1-14)
  - Ledger of [Joseph Byers], n.p., 1806-1817., 16 pages. (Volume MsV. 1, Box-folder 5:1)
    Ledger contains accounts for the sale of parts for wells and the repair of wells.
  - Ledger of [Joseph Byers], n.p., 1814-1819., 8 pages. MsV. 2 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Ledger of [Joseph Byers], n.p., 1814-1821., 12 pages. MsV. 3 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Ledger of Joseph Byers, n.p., 1816-1840., 28 pages. MsV. 4 (Box-folder 5:4)
    Ledger contains varied farm and labor accounts, 1832-1840; also including accounts for the sale of parts for wells and the repair of wells, 1816.
  - Ledger of [Joseph Byers], n.p., 1819-1820., 12 pages. MsV. 5 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Ledger of Samuel C. Byers, 1821-1859, and R[obert] C. Byers, 1870-1874, merchants and farmers, [Augusta County, and Rockingham County, Virginia], 1821-1874., 90 pages. MsV. 6 (Box-folder 5:6)
    Ledger includes sale of farm products and records of laborers; also including record of costs for schooling 3 scholars, 1848.
  - Ledger of Joseph Byers, n.p., 1829-1832., 21 pages. MsV. 7 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Account book containing miscellaneous accounts of Joseph and Samuel C. Byers, 1829-1835., 5 pages. MsV. 8 (Box-folder 5:8)
    Ledger includes mention of the sale of parts for wells or the repair of wells
  - Handwritten textbook in mathematics and bookkeeping, 1843., 100 pages. MsV. 9 (Box-folder 5:9)
    Handwritten textbook in mathematics and bookkeeping, containing various mathematical rules and principles as applied to Federal money and English money; different rules on weighing for various products such as fuel, gold, or medicine; and rules for measuring cloth, land, dry substances or liquid substances; including practice exercises; also including an insert of additional practice exercises, intricate lettering, and poetry, completed by James A. Frame, 1843.
  - Account book containing miscellaneous accounts of Robert C. Byers, 1869., 12 pages. MsV. 10 (Box-folder 5:10)
    Ledger concerns the sale of grain.
  - Account book of R[obert] C. Byers, n.p., 1873-1879., 7 pages. MsV. 11 (Box-folder 5:11)
    Ledger contains miscellaneous farm and labor accounts.
  - Account book, 1878-1879., 62 pages. MsV. 12 (Box-folder 5:12)
    Account book containing records of taxes, licenses, and clerks fees kept by the deputy treasurers for [Augusta County, Virginia?] including C. S. Byers, J. R. N. Speck, S. B. Stover, S. N. Patterson, and others. Includes an index.
  - Reportbook containing grades for Lelia Byers at Old Fort Seminary, Fort Defiance, Virginia, 1895-1896., 8 pages. MsV. 13 (Box-folder 5:13)
    Reportbook was signed by Rebecca Byers and R[obert] C. Byers.
  - Pierce's Memorandum and Account Book used for personal and farm accounts by R[obert] C. Byers, 1902., 17 pages. MsV. 14 (Box-folder 5:14)
    Pierce's Memorandum and Account Book contains printed advertising for various medicines, including "Dr. Pierce's Compound Extract of Smart Weed," and several others.